http://www.lottery.co.uk/privacy-policy

Lost Tickets
What Happens When You Win?
Syndicates
More...
Privacy Policy
We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; this policy sets out how we will treat your personal data.
By using our website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy. For further information on cookies, please read our Cookie Policy.
What data do we collect?
We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:
Identity Data including first name and last name.
Contact Data meaning your email and postal address.
Entry Data means details about entries you have made on our website including the numbers and draws you have entered.
Technical Data means details about the device(s) you use to access our website including your IP address, browser type and version, location, operating system and referral source.
Profile Data includes your login data plus any other optional information that you choose to give to us in your profile such as telephone number, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services. This includes your navigation through the site like how long you might spend on one of our webpages and which page you look at next, page response times and page interaction information such as site searches.
Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us, third-parties and your communication preferences.
How is your personal data collected?
Personal Data is only collected when you use our website and choose to enter one or more of the free draws or to create an account on the site.
Some data may also be collected if you email us for any reason, but only that data which is required to answer your queries.
How do we use your personal data?
Personal Data submitted to us via this website will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website.
We may use your personal data to:
Administer the website.
Improve your browsing experience by personalising the website to reflect your specific areas of interest.
Enable your use of the services available on the website.
Supply to you the services purchased via the website.
Send you general or marketing communications.
Send you information or email notifications which you have specifically requested.
Send you any newsletters and/or marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you and where you have specifically agreed to receiving this information by email. You can opt out of receiving this information at any time by emailing or writing to us using the details provided on our Contact Us page.
Send you invitations to enter any promotions or competitions we may from time to time offer our visitors.
Deal with enquiries and complaints made by you relating to the website.
Keep the website secure and prevent fraud.
Verify compliance with International Laws and the terms and conditions governing the use of the website.
We will not provide your personal data to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing if you have unsubscribed from the service.
Disclosures
We may disclose your personal data to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy.
We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies (this means our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy.
In addition, we may disclose your personal data:
To the extent that we are required to do so by law.
In connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings.
In order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention.
To the purchaser (or prospective purchaser) of any business or asset that we are (or are contemplating) selling.
To any person who we reasonably believe may apply to a court or other competent authority for disclosure of that personal data where, in our reasonable opinion, such court or authority would be reasonably likely to order disclosure of that personal data.
Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.
International data transfers
Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.
Information which you provide may be transferred to other countries including those countries which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Area.
In addition, personal data that you submit for publication on the website may subsequently be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.
Security of your personal data
We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal data.
We will store all the personal data you provide on our secure servers.
All electronic transactions entered into via the website will be protected by encryption technology.
You acknowledge that the transmission of information over the internet is potentially insecure and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.
You are responsible for keeping your password and other login details confidential. While you will require your password to log in to your account, you will never be asked to disclose your password to a representative or employee of the company.
We will cooperate with all law enforcement requests from within or outside the EU.
Policy amendments
We may update this privacy policy from time to time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.
We may also notify you of changes to our privacy policy by email.
This policy was last updated on 16th May, 2018.
Your rights
You may instruct us to provide you with any personal data we hold about you.
As a security measure, to prevent disclosure of your data to anybody who has no right to receive it, we will require evidence of your identity which will include a notarised photocopy of your passport plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address. We reserve the right to request additional information to establish your identify if required and withhold such personal data if required to do so by law.
You may instruct us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes, by emailing or writing to us using the details provided on our Contact Us page.
So long as it is legal for us to do so, you may request the deletion of your data at any time.
Third party websites
The website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or data practices of third party websites including Facebook, Twitter and Google.
Data controller
Take That Ltd. is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as, “we”, “us” or “our” in this Privacy Policy). We are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office and our data protection registration number is Z6413413.
If you have any questions for the Data Controller or about this Privacy Policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact us via our customer contact page and state that your query is for the attention of the Data Controller.
Data retention
We will retain your data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected including any legal, reporting, accounting or insurance requirements.
This is generally 7 years unless the law prescribes a longer period.
So long as it is legal for us to do so, you may request the deletion of your data at any time.
Occasionally we may keep data for a longer period purely for statistical analysis.
Such data is anonymised and cannot be associated with you or your activities.
Contact
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal data, please write to us at our postal address, The Lottery Company Ltd., The Exchange, Station Parade, Harrogate, HG1 1TS or contact us using our Contact page.
Complaints
If you have a complaint, please give us the chance to deal with your issue in the first instance. But you also have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (https://ico.org.uk).
